Caleb Rose

https://www.github.com/CalebRose https://calebrose.io (952) 334-8334 calebrose.mobile@gmail.com

Software Engineer with four years of professional experience providing QA automation and app development for a global manufacturer. I am self-motivated and passionate about designing and developing efficient, functional and creative websites. I am seeking an opportunity as an engineer which will build on my experience, challenge me, and provide an opportunity for earned career advancement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

General Motors

September 2018 - Present

- Implemented unit test coverage using Junit and Mockito libraries, increasing code coverage from 0% to 95%
- Simplified Data Transfer Object structure using Java 8, increasing code maintainability
- Interfaced with users to maintain code application and provide post-launch support through defect fixes and change requests

Software Test Analyst

General Motors

June 2015 – September 2018

- Coded over 300 automation scripts using GM-based selenium framework across three projects covering administrative and plant floor features, decreasing average test time by 70%
- Collaborated with business partners to derive test scenarios from business requirements to validate reports and control room functionality
- Tracked and fixed defects found in SIT testing environment through cooperation with development team, decreasing
 the downtime in app development between sprints
- Provided training and documentation to QA team of five on using internal selenium automation framework to improve productivity on automation coverage

Programming Intern

Argo Group International Holdings

June 2014 - August 2014

- Designed database to store data on underground storage tanks to support underwriters in sales opportunities
- Developed web-application using .NET alongside CIO and director of app development

SKILLS

Proficient: JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Git, MySQL, jQuery, MongoDB **Familiar:** Java, Python, C#, Express, Sequelize, Selenium, Mockito, Junit

EDUCATION

Austin, Texas

University of Texas at Austin

February 2019 - August 2019

Code Bootcamp - Full Stack Development

Notable Technologies: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, Firebase

Waco, Texas Baylor University August 2011 – May 2015

Major: Management Information Systems, B.B.A.

Notable Coursework: System Analysis & Design, Database Management, Cyber Security

PROJECTS

Work Order Wizard App: https://workorderwizard.herokuapp.com
Github Repository: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/WorkOrderWizard/projects/1
Project Board: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/WorkOrderWizard/projects/1

- Designed to track clients' work orders and invoices for customers
- Developed frontend using ReactJs and React Router libraries
- Utilized Firebase and Context API to provide authorization and security both React and Express routes for users
- Secured and stored data using MongoDB

Fast Travel Stocks App: https://fast-travel-stocks-warp.herokuapp.com/
Github Repository: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/FastTravelStocks/projects/1
Project Board: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/FastTravelStocks/projects/1

- Presents users with financial data on video game publishers in an easy-to-read format
- Mapped historical stock data on publishers through CanvasJs library
- Coded application to utilize ReactJs library to meet MVC standards
- Deployed application through Heroku and hosted MySQL database through JawsDB